Hi, my name is Chris from Aquatic Central, here in San Francisco, and on the web at, aquatic-central.com, and I'd like to tell you how to tell, if your fish is sick.
Generally, the easiest way to tell if a fish is sick, is by visual inspection.
Usually, you'll have to get a little bit familiar with how your fish looks, so this will require regular inspections.
That way, you will be able to distinguish when there are differences.
Usually, there will be either fungus, bacteria, or parasitic diseases, or infections.
Most of them can be identified by a visual inspection, either by white tufts, or cottony growths.
There could be small animals growing on your fish.
There could be a loss of coloration, a loss of scale, or rotting, decaying fins.
Usually, it's pretty easy to tell when a fish is sick.
Sometimes, there will be more innocuous symptoms, which will require just behavioral monitoring.
For example, a fish is lethargic, not swimming around, maybe resting at the bottom.
A fish may show signs of rapid breathing.
A fish may show a lack of appetite.
These will be other ways of trying to identify whether your fish is sick.
Again, it's important to try to keep an eye on your fish regularly, to see how he normally behaves, and how he normally looks.
Sometimes, it would also behoove you, to do a little bit of research on the type of fish you have, to see what common ailments they do suffer from.
That way, it will help you to identify when that fish is sick.
Again, this is how you can tell if a fish is sick.
My name is Chris, with Aquatic Central, here in San Francisco, and on the web at: aquatic-central.com.